Contact

talk2ajah@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ajahcs (LinkedIn) www.ajahcs.com (Personal)

Top Skills

JavaScript Nodejs

Python

Languages

Hausa (Elementary)
English (Native or Bilingual)
Spanish (Professional Working)

Certifications

Triplebyte Certified Front End Engineer

Honors-Awards

National Merit Scholar National Merit Scholar

Chukwuemeka Ajah

Software Engineer at Involt Capital Nigeria

Summary

I am a life-long learner who loves working on new challenges and has a knack for finding problems and as well proffering and building solutions to found problems.

I'm competent in developing web application software as well as desktop software using JavaScript, React, VueJS, Python, Django, Flask, NodeJS. Also, bearing in mind the need for data persistence, I'm competent in database technologies such as MongoDB and PostgreSQL, Redis etc.

I've worked with a digital consultancy where I developed new products and maintained existing ones. My capstone project in the digital agency was leading a team of developers to implement a state government web application which helps residents access government services, track projects in their communities and as well as help the government transmit information to state residents. I've also been a software trainer where I taught budding software engineers and programmers programming methodologies and technologies.

Also, I've worked remotely with startups where I help them bring their MVPs to life, develop new product features or maintain existing products.

In my short time as a software engineer, I've trained tens of budding programmers, developed software which led to growth in company sales and improvement in application performance.

Experience

Involt Capital
Software Engineer
July 2020 - Present (7 months)
London, England, United Kingdom

Connectivo Software Engineer April 2020 - July 2020 (4 months) Kungälv, Vastra Gotaland County, Sweden

Connectivo is a business process automation software development company. In my short time there, I worked on the following projects:

I built a payment and accounting automation product that integrates with the top accounting software in the world which invariably helps businesses reduce the time spent in managing their bookkeeping and accurately record their financial transactions.

I designed robust APIs for providing data to frontend React apps using Flask and Django Rest framework.

Led the migration of manual customer onboarding process to a 3-click automated process thereby reducing the time required for new customers to get onboarded and start using our products.

Renterland Software Engineer August 2019 - March 2020 (8 months) Brussels Area, Belgium

Renterland is a property technology startup that is enabling home seekers to create digital renter passports that they can share with landlords and agents thereby fast-tracking their access to quality homes in the United Kingdom and Belgium. While at Renterland, I:

Designed the system architecture for the frontend of our renter passport creation platform with the decision of using React for its implementation and Redux for state management.

Developed the backend API service for interacting with the frontend React app and software administration leveraging highly available services like AWS and Heroku.

Built the back-end subscription (implementing Stripe API) service and AWS S3 file storage service leveraging ExpressJS and NodeJS as well as MongoDB thereby enabling high availability of the platform and trust in the payment process.

Implementation and design of database architecture using MongoDB.

Guided interns on the product direction and participated in code reviews so as to produce quality code as well as improve the coding standards of interns.

Mesh Media Labs
Full Stack Software Engineer
January 2018 - March 2019 (1 year 3 months)
Port Harcourt, Nigeria

Developed digital products based on client requirements and surpassing their expectations.

Led the team on software architecture, system design and requirements.

Built beautiful, responsive web applications such as https://riversstate.gov.ng Helped upstarts build their prototypes thereby enabling them quickly test their ideas and the product fit in the market

Total Shut Down Engineer March 2017 - August 2017 (6 months) Nigeria

Set up and led a team of interns that built a desktop software that would enable interns and new hires to get to know the company and its units and departments' business processes quickly (I was responsible for the programming and team management).

Developed spading plans and flange management documents.

Taught other departments how to prepare the novel flange management documents designed by my team which in turn led to reduced leakages on-site

Education

University of Nigeria, Nsukka
Bachelor of Engineering (B.Eng.), Mechanical Engineering (2013 - 2018)

Air Force Secondary School, Port Harcourt Engineering Science · (2007 - 2013)